user experience is the science
have just
a product like a website or software
application so that it
easy to use so that it fits the
expectations that the user has for it
and so that it meeks business schools
there's a whole
methodology around designing a user
experience in
sometimes people ask me is it worth it
do
all that works design a user experience
so let's talk about the return on
investment
or Rooy doing user experience work
IEEE is set professional organization
that put out reports and does research
for programmers developers and engineers
and
they put out an article called why
software sales
here's some interesting data from
article they estimate that the amount of
money that is spent worldwide
in information technology is estimated
at $1 trillion dollars a year
the percent of projects that are
abandoned
because they are hopelessly inadequate
is up to fifteen percent
that's all projects the percentage
revenue that goes to the
it. create is 5 percent have a company's
total revenue
and up to 10 percent if it's a financial
telecommunications company
the amount of time that programmer spend
on rework that is actually avoidable
is fifty percent of their time the cost
of fixing an error
after development is a hundred times
that fixing
an air before development up the project
is completed
%uh the top 12 reasons that projects
fail
three of the top 12 are directly related
to what we would call user experience
user-centered design work and those
three are badly defined
requirements poor communication among
customers developers and users
and stakeholder politics so the kind of
work that
that user experience professionals do
stakeholder interviews user
researches testing user centered design
these are all things
that can fix at least three of those
twelve reasons
why software sales you actually can
calculate the savings
or additional revenue or benefit that
you get from improving the year
user experience and product so let's
look at some
examples to make this more concrete
first example I want to talk about is
let's say that you
are a micro lending company so these are
of a non-profit organizations that look
for donations from people
and than a take that money and they
landed out in very small loans
to people around the world who
need the money to one a smaller home
business
in order to better their situation so
you have a website
and people donate money at your website
but the searching and donating part at
the interface that the website is
confusing and hard to use
and you have estimated that 50 customers
that de
are actually abandoning before donating
because the poor user experience
so let's do some calculations each
customer let's say donates an average of
fifty dollars
over the course of the year to you are
losing twenty-five hundred dollars a day
or nineteen twelve thousand five hundred
dollars a year
if you spend fifty thousand dollars to
fix the user experience
issues and another fifty thousand
dollars said to rewrite
the code based on those user experience
improvements
we can estimate you can spend a hundred
thousand dollars improving the user
experience
it will take you forty days and will
over a month into realized investment
because you've got nine him twelve
thousand
five hundred dollars a year that she
could improved
sale in a little over a month you've
recouped your investment there are many
measurements
that would be meaningful for example
conversion rate
that's the number that percent increase
in visitors to a website
who either by donated or doesn't hurt to
have to do with money it might be they
take the action weapon take like
register
the website where you might be
interested in a decrease in the number
a person drop us a little bit and then
the decrease in the number of calls to
the help desk
maybe by making use your experience
improvement you can reduce the amount
training that's required for instance if
its internal software application
maybe you wanna increase the usage have
the software application
may be looking to save user time or
maybe you wanna say
development time perhaps airs
or what's what you are trying to reduce
whatever measure you choose
calculating the return on investment is
a way to show
the value up doing user experience work
she is one of my favorite quotes from
albert Einstein
I think he said it best any intelligent
fool can make things bigger and more
complex
it takes a touch of genius and a lot of
courage
to move in the opposite direction
if you'd like your own copy of the
sprawling to download and print
go to human factors dot com
slash are oh I poster
dot ASP